{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Sarcina sickness of beer is caused by", "opta": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optb": "Pedicoccus cerevisiae", "optc": "S. carlsbergensis", "optd": "Zygomonas anaeroium", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Sarcina sickness of beer, caused by Pedicoccus cerevisiae, is characterized by", "opta": "sourness", "optb": "turbidity", "optc": "popiness", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Parsnip like odour and taste in beer is caused by", "opta": "Flavobacterium proteus", "optb": "Zygomonas anaeroium", "optc": "Lactobacillus patorianus", "optd": "S. carlsbergensis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A special beer yeast of the bottom type is", "opta": "S. cerevisiae", "optb": "S. carlsbergensis", "optc": "S. thermophillus", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the fermentation of fructose results in the bitter product mannitol, the fermentation is sometime termed as-", "opta": "mannkic", "optb": "mannitic", "optc": "amertume", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heavy, thick, slimy film of bacteria in the slow process of vinegar manufacture reduces", "opta": "the rate of hydrogenation", "optb": "the rate of acetification", "optc": "the rate of esterification", "optd": "the rate of purification", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following beer is of Japanese origin with an alcohol content of 14 to 17%?", "opta": "Sake", "optb": "Pulpue", "optc": "Sonti", "optd": "Lager", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The crushed grapes used for wine manufacturing are also known as", "opta": "wort", "optb": "must", "optc": "hop", "optd": "pilsener", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The potential spoilage organism in beer is", "opta": "Saccharomyces diastaticus", "optb": "S. carlsbergensis", "optc": "S. cerevisiae", "optd": "S. lactis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the mash in the brewhouse is held too long it may undergo", "opta": "butyric acid fermentation", "optb": "lactic acid fermentation", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "citric acid fermentation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The spoilage most commonly occurring in wine is tourne which refers to", "opta": "acid formation from aldehyde and ketones", "optb": "acid formation from sugars, glucose and fructose", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gassiness resulting from the liberation of carbon dioxide by hetero fermentative lactics is called", "opta": "pousse", "optb": "amertume", "optc": "mannitic", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fermentation of wine can be carried out using the strains of", "opta": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optb": "Saccharomyces carlsbergenesis", "optc": "Bacillus subtilis", "optd": "Pedicoccus cerevisiae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acetic acid bacteria spoiling musts and wines are inhibited by", "opta": "5-7% alcohol by volume", "optb": "14-15% alcohol by volume", "optc": "24-25% alcohol by volume", "optd": "30-35% alcohol by volume", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The micro-organisms causing wine spoilage are", "opta": "wild yeast", "optb": "moulds", "optc": "bacteria", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most important species of vinegar bacteria causing sliminess is", "opta": "Acetobacter aceti", "optb": "Saccharomyces carlsbergiensis", "optc": "Lactobacillus lactis", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an ale type of beer?", "opta": "Weiss beer", "optb": "Porterr", "optc": "Stout", "optd": "Pilsener", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "S. patorianns can cause", "opta": "cloudiness in beer", "optb": "ester like taste in beer", "optc": "stringent taste in beer", "optd": "bitter taste", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}